Contact

hi@dothanhlong.org

www.linkedin.com/in/thanh-long-do (LinkedIn) dothanhlong.org/ (Personal) opengis.vn/ (Company) github.com/soiqualang (Other)

Top Skills

OSGEO

Python (Programming Language) implement technology strategy

Certifications

GIS and Remote Sensing
ESRI ArcGIS Desktop Professional

Honors-Awards

Giải thưởng cuộc thi sản phẩm sáng tạo dành cho thanh thiếu niên tp. HCM

Giải thưởng cho cuộc thi Tài năng khoa học trẻ Việt Nam do Quỹ sáng tao kỹ thuật Việt Nam (VIFOTEC)

Giải thưởng Holcim prize

Giải thưởng Eureka của Thành Đoàn tp. Hồ Chí Minh

Publications

Xây dựng hệ thống hiển thị thông tin khí tượng thủy văn bằng công nghệ mã nguồn mở

A WebGIS Solution for Estimation Landuse Affected by Salinity Intrusion: Case Study in Ben Tre Province, Vietnam

Ứng dụng công nghệ mã nguồn mở trong xây dựng WebGIS phục vụ công bố thông tin khí tượng – thủy văn

Nghiên cứu công nghệ 3D xây dựng mô hình ngập trên nền WebGIS khu vưc tp. Hồ Chí Minh

Building agricultural information system in An Giang Province

Thanh Long Do

Researcher at Vietnam National Space Center - VNSC Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

I have more than 10 years of experience in geospatial analysis and apply it to solve manage and making decision support in Land Use/ Land cover change, deforestation detection, urban planning and environmental managerment in Vietnam. Beside, I also have practical experiences in project management and human resource training skill that been accummulated from projects which I joined. I also have the strength and capability to build and deploy GIS, WebGIS, and GIS Database systems with the goal of effectively managing resources, environment, and assets. My expertise in this area is extensive, and I am confident that I can create systems that are both powerful and efficient. Additionally, I have a thorough understanding of the technologies involved in GIS systems, such as mapping tools, database management, and web technologies, allowing me to develop and deploy systems that are tailored to the specific needs of clients.

Experience

Open GIS Vietnam

2 years 5 months

Managing Director

January 2022 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Develop and implement business strategies;
- Manage financial performance;
- Build and maintain relationships with stakeholders;
- Provide leadership to the company;
- Ensure compliance with legal and regulatory requirements;
- Manage the company's operations;
- Monitor and evaluate performance.

Founder

January 2022 - Present (2 years 5 months)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Idea generation and market research;
- Develop a business plan;
- Seek partners and employees;
- Financial management;
- Build customer relationships;
- Strategic decision-making;
- Manage and grow the company.

VinaGIT

5 years

Chief Technology Officer 2019 - Present (5 years)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

- Develop and implement technology strategy;
- Manage technology operations;
- Lead technology development;
- Collaborate with other departments;
- Stay up-to-date with industry trends;
- Manage technology budgets;
- Recruit and develop technology talent.

Co-Founder

2019 - Present (5 years)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

VINAGIT is a company which provide Geoinformation and spatial data solutions in Vietnam. In the spatial analysis specialist role I joined some projects that related to Real Estate Valuation Information System, spatial data transformation and processing, human resources training in GIS field, ...etc

Vietnam National Space Center - VNSC GIS Team Leader 2018 - Present (6 years)

List of the second (or years)

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

I am currently the research group leader, developing GIS, WebGIS, and remote sensing products at the Ho Chi Minh City Space Technology Application Center, under the Vietnam Space Center - Vietnam Academy of Science and Technology. My group's products include a series of WebGIS systems to serve water management, agricultural information for the Mekong Delta and Central Vietnam region.

Ho Chi Minh City Institute of Resources Geography 4 years

Researcher January 2013 - 2017 (4 years) Vietnam

Scientific Researcher 2013 - 2017 (4 years) Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

I have more than 4 years of experience as a junior and senior researcher at the Institute of Geography of Ho Chi Minh City under the Vietnam Academy of Science and Technology. My major is GIS and Remote Sensing analysis, building WebGIS applications to solve demand in environmental management, deforestation detection, urban planning, etc.

Education

UNIVERSITY OF SOCIAL SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES (USSH) Master's degree, Environmental and Resource Management · (2017 - 2019)

UNIVERSITY OF SOCIAL SCIENCES AND HUMANITIES (USSH)
Bachelor's degree, Geography, Cartography, Geographic Information Systems
(GIS), Remote sensing fields · (2009 - 2013)